hey folks David to from Barb ben.com and
today we're recapping the action from
the 2023 Rogue Invitational in Round
Rock Texas we're going to cover three
big divisions today the men's side for
CrossFit the women's side for CrossFit
and the Strongman Competition which was
men's open competitors So Pro strongman
competitors in the heaviest division but
before we get into that make sure you
subscribe to barbin on YouTube and if
you want really really really indepth
event by event breakdowns we've got all
that including a full leaderboard for
all three divisions at Barb bed.com
context on the Rogue Invitational it's
sponsored by Rogue Fitness not super
surprising there the Rogue Invitational
has become one of the Hallmark events in
strength Sports over the last few years
there's the CrossFit side the strongman
side the legend side Rogue is really
building a Cool brand around this
competition or at least a brand with a
lot of staying power so a lot of eyes
are on and if you're a fan of multiple
strength Sports we are at barbend
obviously it's why we started a sight
about it you get to follow along with
athletes from several different sports
at once now we don't know if there are
any plans to introduce additional
divisions or Sports to the Rogue
Invitational the coming years but the
synthesis of CrossFit and strongman is
pretty nifty and a really spectator
friendly combination as far as following
along we were pretty captivated all
weekend at Barbed not going to lie dog
man CrossFit right in our wheelhouse you
can find full Recaps of every event and
the full competition for every division
at Barb ben.com and at the link in the
description below but let's break down
the winners from the CrossFit
competition all right on the women's
side in the CrossFit portion of the
Rogue Invitational look all eyes are on
TIA Clair Tumi she missed this year's
CrossFit Games because she gave birth
just five or sixish months ago depending
on when you're watching this video we do
know Tia trained through through most of
her pregnancy and got back to training
pretty quickly after giving birth but
the question on everyone's mind was how
quickly can she bounce back is she
actually going to be a threat at this
competition she literally just gave
birth about half a year ago I mean in
the calendar year 20203 she did that and
she basically put any questions to rest
Tia clar Tumi is back she is at the top
of her game or at least at the top of
the game but Tia Clair Tumi didn't quite
win Laura Horvath the reigning fittest
woman on earth who won the CrossFit
games this year again a CrossFit games
where Tia did not compete as an
individual well Horvath was able to Edge
out Tumi to take the crown and it is
horvath's second Rogue Invitational
victory in a row Horvath who's from
Hungary put on a super consistent
performance including three event wins
she finished with 780 points and Tumi
finished with 770 points Emma Lawson
finished in third I do want to point out
that that Tumi actually started off the
weekend with an event Victory and Tumi
and Horvath were tied in points heading
into the final event on Sunday now had
they ended up tied in points overall in
the weekend Horvath actually would have
won because she had the best tiebreaker
she had the most event wins but Tumi and
horbath were going neck and neck Tumi
actually LED for part of the weekend
again she won the first event out of the
gate and she looked great maybe not
quite as dominant as during the middle
of her stretch of six consecutive
CrossFit Games championships but she's
still force to be reckon with in a
stacked field so yeah Tia clar Tumi
she's back she's automatically a threat
for next year's CrossFit Games is this a
rivalry now Horvath scoring a win over
Tia clar Tumi when Tia had been
undefeated for so many years in CrossFit
competition it's a pretty big deal and
honestly it makes next year's season
really exciting on the women's side all
right it was a heavily Canadian Podium
on the men's side Patrick velner
finishes in first place Jeffrey Adler
also from Canada who won this year's
CrossFit Games finished in second place
and Roman krenov finished in bronze
medal position Bren fikowski also from
Canada just outside the podium in fourth
place overall Ricky Gerard of Australia
makes his return to competition after
having to sit out a portion of last
season he finished in fifth place
overall also worth noting that fikowski
and krenov actually tied in points but
krenov takes the edge and finishes in br
middle position because he had better
tiebreakers these were tight divisions
on both the men's and women's sides
Laura Horvath beat T Clair Tumi by just
10 points to take first place overall
Patrick velner beat Countryman Jeffrey
Adler by just 20 points to take first
place overall it was a really exciting
competition and I think the format and
length really a lot shorter about half
the events of what we're normally used
to seeing at the CrossFit Games almost
makes each event a little bit more
impactful it led to tighter races and I
I really enjoyed following along with
this weekend's action I thought it was
pretty spectator friendly because you
were actually able to track things over
the course of 3 days and it wasn't so
much of a slog I mean the athletes
seemed like they could go out and give
it their best to be honest toward the
end of some CrossFit Games iterations
you do see athletes really start to be
ground down injuries accumulate nagging
pains fatigue but this is really
exciting the athletes were clearly
giving it their absolute all until the
very end so I really like this year's
competition format super exciting to
watch on both the men's and women's side
for the CrossFit division all right
let's talk about the strongman portion
of the Rogue Invitational at the top
more Canadian dominance they had a
really good weekend Mitchell Hooper the
reigning World's Strongest Man was
consistent throughout the weekend and he
comes away with a win Tom stolman a
former two-time World's Strongest Man
finished in second place and Matas kilis
Kowski of Poland finished in third place
overall it's a really important and good
return to form for kulus Kowski he has
had a number of injuries and withdrawals
over the last two years about four to
five years ago we saw him as a big
Podium threat at basically any
competition he entered and then it's not
like he dropped off the face of the map
but those injuries piled up he took some
time away from competition he had those
withdrawals great to see KES Kowski who
is truly a fan favorite and a bit of a
static monster when he wants to be back
on the podium back in really good form
next year's men's open strongman
division could be one of the widest
broadest most exciting Fields we've ever
seen across competitions oh also Thor
bjornson has his sight set on returning
so yeah there is a Top Dog in men's open
strong man it's Mitchell Hooper of
Canada but there are like 10 competitors
who on any given day have a really good
shot at making the podium maybe even
winning super super exciting time well
that wraps up the action from this
year's Rogue Invitational again if you
want full I mean really really indepth
to the event coverage check out the link
in the description below we cover all
that on barbend until then I'm David TOA
thanks for tuning
in